{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "Who is known for creating the Campbell's Soup Cans artwork?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Andy Warhol",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Roy Lichtenstein",
              "Jean-Michel Basquiat",
              "Keith Haring"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Andy Warhol, a leading figure in the visual art movement known as pop art, created the iconic Campbell's Soup Cans artwork in 1962, which became a symbol of pop art's critique of consumer culture."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What year did the iconic Marilyn Monroe portrait by Andy Warhol debut?",
            "TrueAnswer": "1962",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "1967",
              "1956",
              "1974"
            ],
            "Explanation": "In 1962, Andy Warhol's famous silkscreen painting of Marilyn Monroe, aptly titled 'Marilyn Diptych,' was first displayed."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is considered the pioneer of stencil street art?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Banksy",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Shepard Fairey",
              "Invader",
              "JR"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Banksy, an anonymous England-based street artist, is known for his politically charged and thought-provoking stencil graffiti artworks."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which artist created the 'Hope' poster featuring Barack Obama?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Shepard Fairey",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Banksy",
              "Obey",
              "JR"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Shepard Fairey gained global recognition for his 'Hope' poster created for Barack Obama's 2008 presidential campaign, becoming an iconic symbol of hope and change."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What type of art is characterized by bold colors and consumer product imagery?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pop Art",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Abstract Expressionism",
              "Surrealism",
              "Cubism"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Pop art, which emerged in the 1950s, is distinguished by its use of bold colors, consumer product imagery, and elements of popular culture, challenging traditional notions of art."
          },
          {
            "Question": "When did Jean-Michel Basquiat's street art career begin?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Late 1970s",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Early 1980s",
              "Mid 1990s",
              "Late 1980s"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Jean-Michel Basquiat began his career as a street artist in the late 1970s under the pseudonym 'SAMO,' before transitioning to galleries and gaining prominence in the 1980s art scene."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who co-founded the iconic 1980s street art movement 'SAMO'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Jean-Michel Basquiat",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Banksy",
              "Shepard Fairey",
              "Keith Haring"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Jean-Michel Basquiat, alongside Al Diaz, co-founded the 'SAMO' graffiti duo, leaving cryptic messages across New York City and garnering attention from the art world."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which street artist is known for his 'Space Invader' mosaic artworks?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Invader",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Banksy",
              "Shepard Fairey",
              "JR"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Invader, a French street artist, gained recognition for creating pixelated mosaic artworks inspired by the classic 'Space Invaders' video game, which he installed in cities worldwide."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the title of the famous urban art project carried out by JR?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Inside Out Project",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Face2Face Project",
              "Wrinkles of the City Project",
              "Unframed Project"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Inside Out Project, initiated by JR, is a global participatory art project that allows people to share their portrait and express their untold stories through oversized posters pasted in public spaces."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which iconic American artist is known for his 'Love' graphic?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Robert Indiana",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Roy Lichtenstein",
              "Keith Haring",
              "Jean-Michel Basquiat"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Robert Indiana, an influential figure in the pop art movement, achieved fame for his 'Love' graphic, which became one of the most recognizable symbols in contemporary art and popular culture."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}